You you start on April 7th. Is that
correct? Yep.
What's the
How do you create
an off-season program as a head coach
for the first time in the
Well, you take from where you've been
before. I think that's where you start
with the off-season. And then we have we
get an extra
non-mandatory mini-camp, which will be
the week of the draft.
Which will be great to be able to get on
the field with them.
So, that'll be
that'll be
exciting for us to get started there,
but
it's really no different. We'll start on
April 7th.
And phase one
just get a chance to talk football and
get the guys acclimated to the
conditioning process. Is that the first
day quarterbacks see the playbook?
It's the first day that we're able to
work with them on the playbook.
They have them in possession? They have
the ability to look at what we've
already have what we already have.
That's my thoughts, yes.
But we cannot coach them on it.
What have been your like your
conversations with the players been like
that that you've been able to have in
the last couple of months? What's been
How would you How would How would you
sort of characterize those those
those conversations? With With the
players, I mean, when you've been able
to just interact with them when they're
in the building or It's been fine. When
they've come through the building or
when we've got a chance to talk to them
on the phone or by text message, it's
been fine. Have you been able to talk to
Miles? We've talked back and forth. He
has not been in the building as far as I
know, so I have not seen him.
Well,
I wouldn't say they're going to be
evenly dispersed, but we'll definitely
disperse them to give ourselves a chance
to at least
evaluate who we have on the roster,
whoever that might be as we go through
the off-season. I know you said ideally
you would like to go into training camp
like knowing who the starter is, but is
that is that realistic especially given
like Deshaun is a player who hasn't
really played live game reps
in you know, almost three years now?
Well,
you'd love to be able to come out of the
spring with a depth chart. That doesn't
mean there's still not competition.
But I do think you have to narrow the
reps
that you or at least balance up the reps
of who you anticipate has come out of
the spring
certainly in a position to be a starter.
How does a one quarterback take the lead
prior to training camp?
By their play every day. I think every
player does that throughout the
off-season.
Not only do they learn the system, but
obviously there's got to be some
competition
in terms of what you do for the
betterment of eight weeks cuz two of the
weeks you're not even on the field, but
the other eight weeks, what you see on
an everyday basis. Again, it's just a
small sample size cuz we don't have the
pads on. So, it's mostly a mental
competition at that point.
>> Some of it can be that way, but
obviously when you get into OTAs or you
get into mini-camp, there is competition
that takes place within the rules. So,
yeah, I think you'll have a better idea
of
each position
what their play looks like and then you
take that into
training camp, which is the closest
thing you'll have to playing the games.
Todd, when you evaluate draft
quarterbacks, do you like to work them
out? Do you feel like you get enough
I think working quarterbacks out is a
piece of that.
I wouldn't say that's the obviously the
most important piece of any player is
their film.
What they do
either in the NFL when you're looking at
free agents or in the draft, what
they've done at the college level. I
think workouts
can be deceiving. Good or bad.
It's weighed. It's a factor.
When you When you are evaluating
quarterbacks, how much do you take into
account how the other 10 guys in the
huddle or the other guys they work with
respond to them?
That's a part of it. That's a big part
of it.
Players being able to have a belief in
whoever that player is.
That's a huge part of it.
But ultimately, it's what they
the players' belief also comes with how
those players play on the field.
Todd, how much with this specific draft
class
you recruited a lot of these guys while
you were at Georgia, whether it was
Tyree or Garrett or or Cade. How much
does that benefit you in terms of
pre-established relationships with some
of these guys as you're evaluating them?
Some, but that
people change over three or four years.
I really haven't looked at much film
from the past of Deshaun. I know he's
going to be part of the roster and I
know he's played at an elite level in
the past. And we're excited to get to
work with him. I know he's excited about
getting back here and getting to work.
I remember when you arrived in
Baltimore, you spoke about wanting to
really empower our backs in the line of
scrimmage and really give them that full
autonomy.
As you start to evaluate these
quarterbacks, are you approaching it
with the same mindset that you want to
give them full autonomy at the line of
scrimmage? Does that Does that kind of
play into the the quarterback
competition decision?
Sure.
I think the the more you empower any
player any person
gives you the
I mean, the optimal opportunity
to get the most out of them.
The more you empower somebody. Now, that
just happens to be the quarterback
position.
What's been your first impressions of
Shedeur and how do you evaluate him in
the quarterback competition?
Well, it's too early to really evaluate
him other than it's been great that he's
been in the building.
It's It's refreshing to see a player
that recognizes where he's at and where
he wants to get to.
And Gabriel hasn't been in the building?
As far as I know, he has not. I have not
seen him in the building yet.
Deshaun was in early when I got the job,
so I got a chance to sit down with him.
It went great.
No, he seemed excited and ready to go.
Again, time will tell.
Have you figured out what that horse's
head gift was all about?
It was my birthday.
No, I mean, there was more than that. It
was just happened to be my birthday.
I haven't really drilled down yet
exactly
What was the relevance in him choosing a
horse? He said he really liked it.
Did he get one for himself?
He said he was going to, but he he
hasn't yet. What is it Is it ceramic or
glass or what?
I think it's I don't even know what
porcelain is, but it felt porcelain.
It was a clay or
somewhat heavy.
But it's a horse. Where is it? But it's
It's right in between
the Browns helmets right behind my desk.
Yep.
I just left it there. He's been in so
often. You know, you change out pictures
of people that come to the house.
Cousins, aunts, uncles, relatives to
make it whoever shows up. He comes in
the most often, so I have his horse in
it. If Deshaun gave me a an elephant,
then I'd have the elephant up there as
well.
Todd, um given like the different stops
you've had in college and and the NFL,
what's maybe like your philosophy on on
building out the wide receiver room in
terms of skill sets and what you're
looking for in in that room?
Well,
I mean, it's real simple.
Big, fast, physical, ball skills,
run after catch. I mean, of course,
that's what everybody's looking for.
But I do think like any position, you're
looking for a player that what is their
elite trait?
How can you continue to develop and
round out the rest of their game? And
how does it fit into what you want to do
offensively?
Todd, when you look at this
specifically this tackle group and and I
and you sort of peruse it.
Do you see a relative lack of guys that
are true left tackles in it compared to
maybe some other cuz it seems like a lot
of the top guys are right tackles
who they're talking about flipping to
the other side. Do you believe that to
be the case?
Um haven't drilled down that far into
position specific. We've looked at all
of the players.
Have a pretty good idea of where
we have them stacked. Andrew will have
to speak more on that, but I think
there's excellent depth in the old line
room. And
in some ways left tackle and right
tackle
sure, it's important the left tackle
with a right-handed quarterback, but
I know this,
when T.J. Watt lines up on the right
side,
you'd feel a lot better if you had a
really good right tackle. I mean, if my
when my we were playing Miles and he
jumps over there,
we're not going to jump we weren't going
to jump Ronnie Stanley over there, so
you really need two tackles. Um
certainly the left side is is critical.
Where do you envision Hal Jenkins in the
in the coming year on the line? Does he
look like a center? Haven't gotten there
yet. Certainly, we'd love for him to
play guard. But he does give us the
flexibility to play him at center
depending on how the draft and our
roster shakes out as we get closer to
the season, but I love his flexibility.
Give me that again. In the early part of
the off-season
conditioning
Not at the facility.
Not the first 2 weeks. Still can't throw
at the facility. Well, shouldn't say
that. First 2 weeks they can, we just
can't be on the field with them.
Then after that we'll be on the field
with them. You'll gauge a little bit of
where they're at from a physical
standpoint and a mental standpoint, but
until you actually
get into phase three or the the the
actually the
other mini camp we have that's not
mandatory,
you really don't understand yet or
you're not getting to uh really drilling
down into where they're at. And then the
final piece then training camp in the
preseason.
So that mini camp the week of the draft
Yes, sir.
It's 3 days, yes. Just like a mandatory
mini camp it is
time it is voluntary.
But you could the time is the exact
same. They can be there for 10 hours up
to 10 hours a day, 24 hours over 3 days.
You can practice.
You just don't have a The difference is
normally when you run your your other
mini camp you have all the rookies.
You have the players that have to be
there. So we're probably looking at
anywhere from 45 to 50 players. So rep
wise you certainly can't
can't rep like you would in a mandatory
mini camp. You could rep 7 on 7?
Everything. Everything you can rep just
like an OTA practice. In that first time
when you get them and you can do
football stuff, how do you
How do you divide the reps for the
quarterbacks? Will they be divided
evenly? Do you shift or I don't
anticipate them being divided evenly.
Even at the very beginning? I don't see
it that way.
I would just say it's our job to make
any player feel comfortable wherever we
put them.
Certainly a player is going to be feel
more comfortable where they played the
majority of their snaps either at the
collegiate level or the NFL level, but
certainly it's our job to I mean I just
read the other day that Sewell's going
to move be moved to left tackle. Well,
if you're a great player, you ought to
be able to play left or right tackle,
right? Don't
don't restrict yourself to what I can
and can't do. I don't I would never want
to say that about a coach or a player.
So you said that the reps aren't going
to be divided evenly. So I assume like
somebody's going to get more reps.
Without, you know, looking at Deshaun's
prior film or knowing how they fit in
your offense, how do you decide who
is kind of QB1
in terms of to start the offense or not?
By basically what we've seen in the past
and where the year ended last year.
So is that each of them against the
board for the reps or is I'm not ready
to say that yet.
I just said the reps The reps can't be
divided up evenly. There's no chance of
them being divided up evenly.
At least on a daily basis.
It's not ideal.
I was at Georgia I think we had a four
or five-way competition my first year
there, the COVID year, and that was not
ideal.
Oh, great question. Um
Well, working for Kirby Smart.
Let's just put it that way. One of the
elite coaches
at any level.
His work ethic, what he demands from
players,
I think
it's hard to
to not benefit from. Just like being
with John Harbaugh.
The last 6 years being with those two
coaches, I think
really
gives you a pathway into
um
confronting anything that gets in the
way of winning football.
Todd,
Dawand Jones and
the center Luke Wypler,
will they be ready for OTAs?
Don't know that. I'm hopeful that by the
end of OTA by the end of offseason we'll
have them, but I don't know that for
sure yet.
Why do you think the league keeps
skewing toward young offensive minds and
why won't they give older guys a chance?
I mean
you and
McCarthy get a third time around, but it
just it doesn't seem to normally go that
way.
Why do you think that is?
Oh, I don't I don't know.
I don't
I don't know exactly why other than
I think there's a lot of really good
coaches out there.
I think the league is trending towards
head coaches. I know it's trending
towards head coaches calling their own
plays.
So I would also say that a lot of the
non-play calling OCs or defensive
coordinators are going to be young
coaches.
That's the way it's going to play out.
It used to be
there was probably about half of the
head coaches in the NFL called their
called offense or defensive plays, and
now you're looking at almost 80% I think
I counted up. So I think there's fewer
and fewer older coordinators. I think
that's part of it. Were you starting to
run out of patience at all? Were you
starting to run out of patience and
wondering if this was ever going to
happen?
No. No.
Wasn't meant to be. It's not meant to
be. I mean, being an offensive
coordinator in the NFL is pretty damn
cool.
I mean, if that would have been the end
of it,
then awesome. I mean, that's you're
still one of the top 32 in the world at
what you do, and I can't make decisions
for people.
You can only do the job that you have,
try to do it the best of your ability,
and if it works out, it works out.
Coming into the organization here in
your first year with a quarterback
battle, can you speak to how you
approach that from a leadership
perspective, like being new to the
organization, how you
manage that? Can you speak if there's
any
advantage necessarily of being, you
know, fresh to, you know, these players
and being a head coach in that regard?
Well, sure. The quarterback leadership's
critical, but that happens organically.
I don't think you can force somebody to
be a leader that's not. I think you can
talk to them about how they carry
themselves, how their practice habits,
their routine.
But I think builds confidence with your
other players players around them.
Um
I can't speak to being new and what
that's going to do.
Um
we'll let let it play out. Right up
in your first year here, will Switzer
come back to the offensive meetings or
will you? I'll run the offensive
meetings. Most of them. I shouldn't say
all of them. There'll be meetings that
Travis will end up running, but for the
most part I'll run the meetings, but we
run them together. The installs are run
together. Every coach has a piece of
that. Most of the coaches will have a
piece of the meetings, but for the most
part I'll run the offensive meetings.
And that's to install things the way you
want. Correct.
Do you have a fullback?
We'd like to have a fullback. Why? Why
is that? What do you What do you think
that is?
I think it's helpful in all the areas
where you have to run the football.
Coming out, 4-minute, short yardage,
goal line.
Especially if you want to be a gap
scheme team. Don't think if you want to
be a zone team per se you'd have to have
that.
But from gap schemes, downhill runs,
and I think in those areas
when you're trying to,
you know,
run the football to a high level, make
them fit gaps, I think there's a benefit
to having that. And we proved that with
Evan Pryor Carter. So would you ideally
like to have someone like in the same
mold as Evan Pryor Carter or you open to
maybe like a lighter body like a Kyle
Juszczyk type or H-back type or Well,
Pat's a unicorn. I mean, 300 lbs and
basically with his athleticism,
having an offensive guard back there
with the field that he has,
I think I think it's just it's rare. So
we're going to look for
any player that we think gives us an
opportunity to run the football to a
high level.
No, I'm excited about the room. I'm
excited about
Shedeur, Deshaun, and Dylan.
I mean, we'll see how it plays out
through the draft or through free agency
of adding another piece to that room.
Early on it was different because you're
hiring.
That That's probably the biggest piece
of it
is hiring a staff.
Cuz you're a part of it in the past,
and I you got to go all the way back to
Southern Miss, but not to the extreme
of the pieces we had to put together
here.
Obviously at two critical spots, special
teams coordinator and the defensive
coordinator position
that I thought would fit well with the
current staff.
So that was that was as much as
anything. Everything else
is getting ready for the draft. It's
football.
It's getting to know players.
None of that's different in my opinion.
What's your philosophy going to be on
playing time in preseason games? You
only have three of them.
Do you favor playing rather than
sitting? I anticipate playing our guys.
How much that'll be determined, but I do
anticipate playing our guys. All three
parts of all three games? I don't know
if I'd say all three, but at some part
of the preseason, I anticipate our guys
playing.
Offensively,
there's going to be a pretty big
learning curve. Might be some
formational things that are similar,
but
defensively, I would anticipate
there's going to be more similarity than
there will be offensively.
You run
a lot of tall personnel and tight ends.
It seems like there's also quite a few
different
looks now
than maybe before.
What's what's the value that you see,
especially in your offense,
to have something like
Well, we were lucky enough at the place
I was before to have a good number of
tight ends. That also
puts you in a position to use that
personnel group. I wouldn't say we're
going to be a 12 personnel group of 21
and 11 until we get out there and see
what we have. Till we get the draft
completed, free agency completed, and
see what we have. I think that's our job
as coaches is to utilize the players
that we have.
And we we morphed a little bit last year
with Isaiah Likely being hurt and Lamar
being hurt to a little bit more 21 than
we were even 12 the year before.
So, we'll see how it goes. I do think
that
the bigger you are, the calmer the
looks.
That doesn't doesn't mean it's an
end-all,
but I think the more open you are,
the variety increases of what you see
defensively, and the more up to speed
your quarterbacks have to be in terms of
protections and checks.
I know you have your approach to the
draft,
but in the back of your mind, you're
sort of thinking about how you can
maybe add to your offense with some of
these guys.
100%.
But, the way it plays out out
also has a
a big part in that because
you could have a player targeted and 30
picks later, he
he didn't make it.
So, it's
you can't say for sure till you get the
roster, and then you go from there. Why
why don't we see much of 21 anymore in
the NFL?
I just think it's a byproduct of starts
in high school.
I think everything trickles down from
that. That's why you're seeing more
athletic quarterbacks.
I mean,
there are still quarterbacks, but in
high school, you're using more athletic
quarterbacks. You're not seeing tight
ends.
Blocking tight ends, they're playing
defensive end.
You don't see fullbacks cuz they don't
exist. So, they're not trained to play
fullback.
Just like Charlie Kolar this past year
in free agency was one of one, a
blocking tight end that could block the
C-gap. In the draft, there are a few
more this year than there has in the
past. So, it's hard to find those guys,
and in a world of winning quickly, how
long do you have to develop a player
that isn't comfortable in that role?
That makes it very, very difficult. The
other is is you get to the point that if
you haven't seen them on tape,
you get to the point, a lot like they've
done in the past here, use an offensive
lineman in the backfield. Um
use an offensive lineman as a as a
blocking tight end. That's where you've
seen more more jumbo packages because
you just don't have those players coming
out in the draft anymore or even playing
it in in high school. I mean, when it
comes to two backs in the backfield,
that's nothing radical.
No, it's not.
>> Running backs all over in high school.
Why why don't NFL coaches use two backs
and both and that as an option to run
You talking about just any backs or
fullbacks in general? Just just two
backs.
It's not that that's not good football.
I just think that
you're comfortable with what you've
done. That doesn't mean that's right.
It's not about being right, it's about
getting it right.
But,
when you don't see it or you're not
around it, I I don't know triple option
football.
So, we're not going to run triple
option. I've been around pieces of two
back, two skill backs.
So, we utilize those pieces. Haven't
committed to more of that
moving forward. Not that that's not
You see it all over the place where you
can still use it as pieces. You just
don't see it as a general rule.
Todd, a lot of a lot has been made about
your affinity for for quarterbacks with
mobility. Um just it's kind of
open-ended, but like how much is like
quote unquote mobility going to play a
deciding factor in who starts at
quarterback?
Well,
I think most coaches would have an
affinity for quarterbacks
that are mobile,
but they're also they also have an
affinity for quarterbacks
that can complete passes
and are really good on third down and
two minute.
And so, that's a big part of it as well.
So,
certainly with the league and the way
it's gone and the multiple looks you get
defensively and the elite rushers that
you get,
it's certainly beneficial
to have a quarterback that can escape,
especially considering the number one
pass play you're going to have in the
NFL is scramble drill.
So, it certainly benefits you to have a
mobile quarterback, but ultimately,
that's just a piece of it.
That's that's a big piece of it, but I
it's also you're not seeing nearly as
many statues of quarterback. They don't
exist. Colleges don't have them. High
schools don't have them. So, they they
really don't exist. I mean,
players that are now considered less
mobile
15 years ago would have been considered
mobile.
They're just not now because it's
completely flipped to where there's a a
lot more
elite mobility guys than there's ever
been.
I think Shador is mobile. He's just not
like some of the others.
Yeah, I wouldn't say that.
No, it's the same offense. It's just a
matter of
whether you want to use that
athleticism. Whether you're
When you install uh
say for instance, you're running draws.
What does it really take to install QB
draw? Draw is already in. If you're
running split zone and you're blocking
the end, what does it really take to
avoid the end and block the alley? It's
just another piece of your offense that
allows for a mobile quarterback to get
on the perimeter. There's other aspects
of that when you have a player like
Lamar that you can take advantage of and
be a little bit
more
extreme
um than you are with with other
quarterbacks, but for the most part, it
doesn't change. As you look at
you know, coaching Lamar, you know, kind
of
now skewed what you you know, when you
look at a quarterback or do you do you
sort of have to factor in look, I'm not
looking at you know, Lamar with such a
one such a unique
that you you take that into account as
you're evaluating other quarterbacks?
I just take it whoever's in the room. I
really don't overthink it that much.
We didn't know Lamar when we got there
or I didn't.
And you evolve as you go. What we
started off with Lamar
when I first got there, in the end,
wasn't drastically different, but it was
different.
I don't I don't know the quarterbacks we
have now
other than what I've seen, and we really
didn't know Lamar, and that's your job
as a coach to evolve and build a system
that fits the quarterbacks you have.
He's a little like Brock Bowers in the
fact that
his his body type is more of an H and F,
run after catch
more than length,
more as a C-gap blocking Y.
So, you love his athleticism.
You like his ability to run after catch,
his ball skills like Brock, very similar
in that regard.
Having coached
in the college level
and now in the NFL as well, do you sort
of see that finding sort of that
those guys ready
Andrew would have a better idea of that
than I would over the years.
I would just say that
I think offenses have changed, the way
teams practiced have changed.
You have more college teams that run no
huddle.
You have more offensive linemen that are
in two-point stances all the time.
I think when you watch players on tape,
O-linemen in college,
their practices and their games
are about stamina. There's no time to
huddle, get right back to the line of
scrimmage.
How you teach O-linemen to finish in
college is difficult.
Cuz how do you have time to finish when
you're right back on the ball?
So, there's certain aspects of the game
that has changed that certainly
I wouldn't say prohibits O-linemen from
developing, that's unfair.
Again, Andrew will be able to speak to
that.
I know the players are more talented
than ever. Their size, their
athleticism,
um their understanding of the game
to me are at
an all-time high. Is there a type of
receiver that you guys might think could
complement what you guys already have?
And what do you kind of make of this uh
draft class?
I don't think there's anyone in
particular
other than we're obviously looking to
add talent.
Todd, uh I think George Warhop was your
first hire. Is
He was one of our first hires.
>> to that?
Oh, without a doubt.
I think hiring Travis Whitzell,
George Warhop,
Danny Briere, Ian Coley,
Jeff Blasko, who was here with me in
'19, and Mike Vrabel, I mean
what an elite staff.
And then to have been with those guys
before and to allow you to get up to
speed quickly,
and
George and I are aligned as Travis and
all of us are in terms of who we want as
our offensive line coach, and that is to
be able to run off the football and make
them deal with us. And that's an
old-school mentality, and that's what we
want. Todd,
Todd, I'm going to ask you as part of
your coaching journey, it began in Tampa
for you as a play-caller at the NFL
level. What was your your takeaway from
your time with Dirk Koetter, Mike Evans,
and Chris Godwin, and
did it help get you here?
Well, first of all, I owe a lot to Dirk.
I mean, Coach Koetter's been
probably my number one mentor in terms
of game planning,
in terms of detail,
how you approach attacking a defense,
being a professional film watcher.
I mean, I wouldn't be where I'm at where
where I'm at without Coach.
But
and I'm certainly appreciative in '18 he
gave me the opportunity to call it,
changed my path forever.
But one thing Dirk's always been about
is
how are you going to be explosive? And
you look at any of his offenses and what
I learned there was
after turnovers,
you want to be really good on offense
and you want to be really good on
defense.
Be explosive and stop explosives. And
that's the nature of the game. And then
there's others that fall in line, but
and we had really good players. So, I've
I certainly
benefited by having those players uh
there, uh James and Fitz and all those
wide outs and the great O-line we had,
but
um wouldn't be where I'm at without
Coach.
Well, I think there's always competition
irrespective of the number of reps a
player gets.
The number of reps a player gets doesn't
eliminate competition.
It's just in a given day,
let's say for instance, you want to see
a quarterback with
the first group, the second group, the
third group.
Well, are you going to divide those reps
up evenly?
Are you going to divide up the reps
everywhere evenly? Um I don't see it
that way. I don't see it That doesn't
mean there's not competition.
I just see it as in a given day, and
it'll be daily in terms of who gets what
reps and when. Cuz we certainly want to
allocate our reps to the players we feel
like are going to give us the best
chance to win.
So, let me make sure I have this right.
So,
on a Monday,
maybe someone gets more reps than on
Tuesday, so someone else starts.
Could certainly be that way. It's not
written It's not written in stone. It's
not like you're going to have like a QB1
Mhm.
On any given day, that's we're flexible
in that. Just like the practice schedule
itself is always flexible. You could ask
me about a practice schedule and we
could change that tomorrow. That's not
written in stone. How players compete,
how they approach their job and their
everyday
uh diligence, that's non-negotiable.
But how we do things, the number of reps
we get,
that's an everyday decision. Todd, when
you say that, you said that you you
really haven't looked at prior Deshaun
film. But why wouldn't you look at, you
know, prior games that he played, even
in Cleveland and like, you know, in the
same way that you watched Shady and kind
of I just haven't drilled down into
that.
Have I watched a little bit of it? Of
course, that is. But there's also some
aspects of it. Okay, so
I would say this.
We have crossover tape. Have I seen
Deshaun Watson play before? Of course.
I saw him play against us when I was in
Baltimore.
Do Did we play the Cowboys 2 years ago
after Cleveland opened up the season
with Dallas? Yes. Is that a great film
to watch Deshaun Watson on? Absolutely
not. I mean, that was not a fun tape to
watch to try and look at that film and
say, "That's Deshaun Watson." It's
unfair. So, I think you want a little
bit cuz I don't know the system they
changed to. I'm making a point here.
When Ken Dorsey came in and what they
were running, I don't know that.
I don't know what they were asking him
to do.
Or the year before when
the Browns came over and beat the Ravens
there. I don't know that. I just know
what I've seen over the years.
I've seen a really good football player.
And we're hoping to be able to tap into
that. I know he's excited and we're
excited to work with him. Like we are
with Dylan, uh like we are with Shady.
Well,
I'll go back to Travis. When I first got
to Baltimore,
Greg Roman had been the offensive
coordinator designing the whole run
game.
Where everywhere else I'd been, the
O-line coach had a huge hand in the run
game. So, when I got there, Joe
D'Alessandris, who's passed away since
then,
he did more of the protections. When I
interviewed Travis
to decide whether just keep him on the
staff, he went through the run game and
absolutely killed it.
And our job was to
mix, blend what I've done in the past,
and then what Lamar did well. And ever
since then, he's just grown leaps and
bounds in all aspects
of his coaching. Not just run game,
dealing with players, pass game, overall
thoughts, philosophically how to attack
people.
Uh we wouldn't have had the success we
had in Baltimore without him.
All right, we got to wrap this up.
Jimmy,
uh
you said yesterday
that
Deshaun feels like
he's getting a fresh start. Do you feel
that way?
In your conversations with him, do you
kind of get the sense that he feels
he's getting a fresh start?
I think so.
I mean,
I spoke to him one day.
I mean, I dated my wife for 5 years
before we decided to get married, so one
day is not enough.
But I will say just like 2 weeks isn't
enough, 2 months isn't enough. It's uh
it's a process.
I will just say this, we're excited to
have him. We're excited to see what he
has. He's part of our roster. Anybody
that's part of our roster, it's our job
as coaches to try and get the most out
of them. Why isn't that
obvious? I don't have any idea. I don't
I don't understand it at all. The most
important part is to put a winning
product on the field.
I don't care who that is, whether
they're on our roster or they're not.
Now, he just happens to be part of our
roster.
And I'm excited to have him along with
the other players we have on our roster.